[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
different approaches of tosca automated
test execution
also i will explain the steps to enable
and generates the document through
docusnapper
test execution is a process to verify
the application functionality based on
the test cases the test execution can be
done manually or through automated
approach
in this video i will guide you to
perform automation test execution in
tosca
tosca allows use to execute the test
cases in two ways
execute test cases in scratchbook and
execute test cases from execution list
trisentis advises using the scratchbook
for a dry run which means to to check
the test case readiness
the scratchbook execution results will
not be available for future reference
we also could perform the execution of
individual test steps
let's see the execution from scratchbook
we need to right-click on the selected
test case and select option run in
scratchbook to initiate the execution
from scratchbook
no need to check out the test case or
containing folder for scratchbook
execution
the automated script will perform google
search and validate the trisentis logo
after opening the trisendis official
portal
[Music]
the temporary execution logs will be
appear in the screen which contains the
logs for each of the steps including
verifications
[Music]
a green tick mark will be shown in each
log step for success condition
in case of failure a red cross mark will
be appeared
the execution segment provides a feature
of selecting and preparing multiple test
cases for execution
execution performed and execution list
will be available for future references
first we need to understand the approach
to create execution list
and enablement of docusnapper before
initiation of execution
the enablement of doka snapper is an
optional step which allows tosca to
create a detailed execution documents
for each of the test case
the docusnapper contains the logs and
the images of each step
let's start with execution list creation
step the execution logs are kept
permanently in execution list
it has to be created in execution
section
[Music]
first we need to dock the execution
section in tosca commander for better
visibility
the default and previously created lists
are displayed here
[Music]
now we will check out the route to
created our own execution list
the execution list cannot be created
directly
first execution list folder has to be
created in the execution section
it can be done by selecting the create
execution list folder icon after right
clicking on checked out folder we can
change the list folder name accordingly
now we can create the execution list
after right clicking on newly created
execution list folder
entering the name as sample execution
list
the next step is to add the test case to
the execution list
we can add the test cases into the
execution list from the test cases
section by the drag drop method
we will add the test case which was
created previously
the multiple test cases can also be
added in this way
the test configuration section contains
the parameters which are defined during
test case development
any changes from here will be applicable
to this list only
initially no logs are available here
by clicking on check in button we can
save the same in the shared repository
now i will show how to enable todoka
snapper to allow tosca to create
documents during the execution
click on project tab which is available
in tosca commander header section and
click on settings
the tosca setting wizard will be
appeared
select the navigation engine and
docusnapper which are available under
settings in left section of the wizard
now select the option docusnapper
we need to change the value of setting
option enable snapper to yes
the different docusnapper configuration
options including document paths can be
customized from here
now close wizard to enable the
docusnapper
now i will show how to trigger the
execution from tosca execution list and
view the document generated through
docusnapper during execution
to execute the test case from execution
list first we need to check out the
execution list
[Music]
now we will be able to initiate the
execution by clicking on run option
after right clicking on the selected
test case
multiple test cases or the entire suite
can be selected for execution
the automated script will perform the
defined test steps including google
search
opening the trisendis official portal
from the search result displayed in the
google page and validate the trisendis
logo
after completion of execution the
execution logs will be available in the
execution list which contains the logs
for each of the steps including
verifications
a green tick mark will be shown in each
log step for success condition
in case of failure a red cross mark will
be appeared now perform the check in
action to store the result permanently
in the shared repository
the docusnapper generated report can be
viewed from the path app data
tricentes
tosca test suite
7.0.0
doka snapper
the report should be available as per
the test case name
it will contains the execution logs and
the screen shot for each of the test
steps
this document will be very helpful for
proofing the test executions
if the execution performed through
scratch book the report name will be
start with text scratchbook
[Music]
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca automated test
execution approaches
we will learn more about data
parameterization and creation tosca
reusable test step block through library
in next tosca tutorial
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query